Wanderse, Winifred Research Notes on Frances Perkins and Incomplete Manuscript 5982
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Winifred Wanderse Research Notes on Frances Perkins and Incomplete Manuscript
1931-1995
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
Wandersee, Winifred
Perkins, Frances
5982
5 cubic feet
5 linear ft.
Records (documents).
Research notes, articles and other publications, and manuscript drafts.
5745655
General
Contact Information:
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation and Archives Martin P. Catherwood Library 227 Ives Hall Cornell University Ithaca, NY 14853 (607) 255-3183 kheel_center@cornell.edu http://www.ilr.cornell.edu/library/kheel-center
Compiled by:
Kheel Staff, November 14, 2013
EAD encoding:
Kheel Staff, April 24, 2019
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the collections in the Kheel Center is restricted. Please contact a reference archivist for access to these materials.
Related Materials
Related Collections: 5017: Frances Perkins Correspondence and Memorabilia 5065m: Frances Perkins Letter to Donald Stetson 5812: Interviews about Frances Perkins 5982: Winifred Wanderse Research Notes on Frances Perkins and Incomplete Manuscript 6002 AV: James S. Perkins Collection of Movie Film Studies of Shop Operations 6027: James Secor Perkins Additional Papers /3012: Alice Cook Papers /3007: Maurice Neufeld Papers /4039: Milton R. Konvitz Papers /4057: James A. Gross NLRB Files /4073: James O. Morris Office Files /4107: Kheel Center Additional Cataloging Project Work notes /4297: ILR School Biography Files 5001 mf: American Association for Labor Legislation Records on Microfilm 5001 mf: American Association for Labor Legislation Records on Microfilm 5002: American Association for Social Security Records 5143: Anna Weinstock Schneider Papers 5221: Max Meyer Papers 5225: ALES Records 5226: National Council On Household Employment Records 5235: National Consumers League Records 5277: Workers Education Bureau of America Records 5549: Edwin S. Smith Papers 5583/5: Archives Organization File (AOF) Part 5 5584: National Archives and Records Service Copies of Federal Documentation on Black Workers 5616: Isaac Max Rubinow Papers 5676: International Fur and Leather Workers Union Records 5709 mf: National Women's Trade Union League of America Records on Microfilm 5724 mf: Cigar Makers International Union Records on Microfilm 5780 AV: ILGWU Audio-Visual (AV) 5780 P: ILGWU Photographs 5780 P N45: ILGWU 4x5 Negatives of Photographs 5780/002: ILGWU David Dubinsky Correspondence 5780/177: ILGWU Communications Department Biography Files
Perkins, Frances, 1880-1965; Wandersee, Winifred.
5745655
- Interviews: Neuman, Beyer, Reilly, Dodson, Wickens, Miss Jay, Coggleshall, 1965-1990 (Box 1, Folder 1)
- List of Archives, 1985 (Box 1, Folder 2)
- Labor Publications, 1993-1995 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  Scope and Contents
  Labor's Heritage and George Meany Center for Labor Studies
- Articles-Perkins Bio Prog. Era, 1965-1989 (Box 1, Folder 4)
- Readings Related to Perkins, 1902-1992 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Reading List Related to Perkins, 1976-1987 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Miscellaneous Material on Perkins: (Hard to File), 1921-1993 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Articles-By Me JAH; Wick; Perkins, 1978-1987 (Box 1, Folder 8)
- Essays and Lectures on Perkins (by me) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  no dates
- Perkins-Intro Material and AHA Paper, 1986-1988 (Box 1, Folder 10)
- NEH Report, 1990-1993 (Box 1, Folder 11)
- NEH-FDR Workshop-Summer 1992, 1990-1992 (Box 1, Folder 12)
- Dept. of Labor, 1933-1948 (Box 1, Folder 13)
- Southwest Labor St. Conf.-March 1991 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  Southwest Labor Studies Conference March 22-23, 1991
- Home Ec./Hist. Conf. Cornell U-for NEH, 1991 (Box 1, Folder 15)
- Southern Labor Studies Conf. - 1991 (Atlanta) (Box 1, Folder 16)
- Copies of 1920's books excerpts, 1924-1928 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  Various copies from books from 1920's
- Chapter IV Notes (Box 1, Folder 18)
- Book III (Box 1, Folder 19)
- Book III (Box 1, Folder 20)
- BK. II - Ind. Com. Politics, 1920 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  FDR in 1920
- Book II (Box 1, Folder 22)
- Book II-Duplicates (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Spargo Strike BK. II, 1919 (Box 1, Folder 24)
- Perkins Reminiscences Book IV U.S. Dept. of Labour 1933-34 and 1st yr. of New Deal pp. 298-332, 1933-1934 (Box 1, Folder 25)
- Perkins Reminiscences Book V 1933-35: The National Recovery Administration, 1933-1935 (Box 1, Folder 26)
- Perkins Reminiscences BK VI 1933-1939 Strikes and Unions (Box 1, Folder 27)
- Perkins Reminiscences BK VII National Labor Relations Act (Box 1, Folder 28)
  no date
- Book IX (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Perkins Reminiscences BK I Background Strike Unions pp. 1-74 (Box 1, Folder 30)
- BK. I WWI Era pp. 385-444 (Box 1, Folder 31)
- Book I - pp. 295+ (Box 1, Folder 32)
- Bk. ! - NY State Leg. - Smith (Box 1, Folder 33)
- Book copies (Box 1, Folder 34)
- Perkins-on Triangle Shirtwaist Factory Commission-Bk. 1 pp. 115-174 (Box 1, Folder 35)
- Book I-Marriage; Legal Name; Early Ambitions pp. 243-55; 67-72 (Box 1, Folder 36)
- Perkins - On Suffrage Feminism pp. 175-202 Book I (Box 1, Folder 37)
- Perkins - On Consumer League 54 Mr. Bill Bk. I pp. 75-114 (Box 1, Folder 38)
- ILR Materials, 1957-1984 (Box 1, Folder 39)
- Lectures by Perkins: Cornell U., 1957 (Box 1, Folder 40)
- Articles and Notes, 1982 (Box 2, Folder 1)
- New Deal for Youth (Paper-1981-1982) (Box 2, Folder 2)
- Reduction of Nonessential Federal Expenditures-Notes, 1981 (Box 2, Folder 3)
- NYA-Youth and Wartime Agriculture, 1938-1942 (Box 2, Folder 4)
- NYA-Educational Committee (College Aid), 1937 (Box 2, Folder 5)
- NYA-Educational Camps for Unemployed Women, 1935-1939 (Box 2, Folder 6)
- Monthly Labor Reviews: Employment Conditions-1930's, 1931 (Box 2, Folder 7)
- Children's Bureau-Employment of Youth, 1934-1936 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Women & Family Economics - 20th Century, 1939-1981 (Box 2, Folder 9)
- Biblio-State Labor Bureau Publications 1899-1902 (Box 2, Folder 10)
- Final Report on WPA Program, 1935-1943 (Box 2, Folder 11)
- CCC - Rawick Thesis (+ bibliography) (Box 2, Folder 12)
- NYA - Youth Employment in Wartime, 1941-1942 (Box 2, Folder 13)
- N.R.A., 1935 (Box 2, Folder 14)
- Library of Congress Acquisitions Manuscript Division 1981 (Box 2, Folder 15)
- The Bright Lexicon of Youth: The New Deal and the American Youth Congress (Box 2, Folder 16)
  5 copies No date
- "The Bright Lexicon of Youth" OAN - 1985 (Box 2, Folder 17)
- Notes - 1930's Paper (Box 2, Folder 18)
  No dates
- " A New Deal for Youth" - Paper - Duquesne University 1982 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Muncy Dissertation, 1987-1988 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- 1930's Papers, 1989-1991 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- New Deal Policy - (PP) - Social Security/Health Insurance/ -Unemployment Ins., 1932-1935 (Box 2, Folder 22)
- New Deal Policy - (PP) - Industrial Planning, 1933-1935 (Box 2, Folder 23)
- New Deal Policy - Youth and Children, 1935-1945 (Box 2, Folder 24)
- NYS - Hist. Conf. - 1987 (Baker, McMurray) (Box 2, Folder 25)
- NEH Proposal, 1988-1989 (Box 2, Folder 26)
- Maurice Neufeld Diary (on FP), 1957-1992 (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Perkins Bio - Notes from Secondary Sources (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Perkins - Primary Sources About Her, 1933-1994 (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Perkins - Letter to Frances White and Lectures at Cornell, 1957-1964 (Box 3, Folder 4)
- "Be Ye Steadfast: Frances Perkins and the Ambivalent Legacy of Gender Politics" (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Chapter VIII (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Perkins Chapters - Early Drafts (Box 3, Folder 7)
- Perkins/ John Andrews Correspondence - ILR School (?), 1918-1930 (Box 3, Folder 8)
- Schlesinger Primary Sources, 1934-1992 (Box 3, Folder 9)
- Perkins - Biography by Mohr, 1992 (Box 3, Folder 10)
- NCL Papers - Notes and Articles, 1910-1944 (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Al Smith, 1919-1936 (Box 3, Folder 12)
- U.S. Dept. of Labor, 1934-1991 (Box 3, Folder 13)
- FDRL File, 1933-1945 (Box 3, Folder 14)
- FDRL - ER Papers, 1934 (Box 3, Folder 15)
- FDRL - Dewson Papers Perkins File, 1932-1955 (Box 3, Folder 16)
- FDRL - Sacks; FDP, Dickerman; Hopkins, 1911-1944 (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Perkins and Women's Bureau (Mary Anderson Papers), 1910-1944 (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Labor Under the New Deal (PP), 1933-1985 (Box 3, Folder 19)
- Emily Smith Warner (Al Smith's Daughter) (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Correspondence: Frankfurter; P. Kellogg, 1933-1934 (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Family Correspondence (Wilson, Perkins, Ramsey), 1990 (Box 3, Folder 22)
- Mt. Holyoke, 1933-1991 (Box 3, Folder 23)
- Writings and Testimonies by F.P., 1916-1990 (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Labor History Article, 1990-1994 (Box 3, Folder 25)
- NLRB Records - ILR, 1934-1935 (Box 3, Folder 26)
- NLRB Interviews - ILR, 1968-1988 (Box 3, Folder 27)
- Conducting Research in FBI Records (1993) (Box 4, Folder 1)
- File Description: Frances Perkins File No. 9-578, 1935 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- File Description: Frances Perkins File No. 62-28592, 1933-1954 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- File Description: Frances Perkins File No.62-55640, 1939-1956 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- File Description: Frances Perkins File No.101-255, 1939-1942 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- File Description: Frances Perkins File No.121-16470, 1943 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Youth Organizations and Programs, 1934-1935 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Soc.- Econ. Status of Am. Youth, 1941-1986 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Radicalism in the 30's, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Matthews, "Fellow Traveler" (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Altbach, Student Politics in Am. The 1930's (1974) (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Women in the 30's (Papers), 1983 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Articles by and about Youth 1930's, 1935-1938 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Dies Committee - HUAC (1930's), 1939 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- "A New Deal for Women" Paper: New Deal Conf. Austin, Texas March 1983 (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Eleanor Roosevelt Centennial Conference Folder, 1984 (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Perkins: History and Notes (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Perkins: Chapters (Box 4, Folder 18)
- "I'd Rather Pass a Law Than Organize a Union" Paper (1990) (Box 4, Folder 19)
- 2 Booklets: "Clara Mortenson Beyer: A Life of Clear Direction " and "Dedication of the Frances Perkins Building" (1980-1990) (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Chapters and Letters, 1992 (Box 4, Folder 21)
- Perkins - Chap. 1 and Contents (Box 4, Folder 22)
- Chapters I-III, 1991 (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Perkins Papers (by me), 1990 (Box 4, Folder 24)
- Labor Papers, Program, and Questionnaire (Box 4, Folder 25)
- "Frances Perkins Meets Tammany Hall" Paper (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Scholarly Papers - Relevant to Perkins Bio, 1987-1988 (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Frances Perkins Meets Tammany Hall Copies and Articles, 1990 (Box 4, Folder 28)
- Perkins - Reformist Approach to Labor - Prog. Era (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Children's Bureau - Unemployed Youth, 1934-1936 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Children's Bureau - Schooling and Scholarship, 1931-1932 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Vocational Education (Labor Dept. - esp. Children's Bureau), 1934-1936 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Children's Bureau - Child Labor, 1933-1935 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Children's Bureau - Continuation Schools, 1929-1932 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Children's Bureau - Child Labor Homework Industry and Agric. Labor, 1933-1941 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Notes and Articles, 1976 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- CPUSA - Youth - 1930's, 1982-1984 (Box 4, Folder 37)
- Notes and Clippings, 1939-1994 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Book Notes (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Hartwick Humanities in Management Institute (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Floppy Disc - 1930's Lab Revised Notes/Perkins Chapters (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Perkins - Columbia Univ. Libraries - Photocopies - Alphabetical Order A-W (1934-1946) (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Perkins Papers - Columbia U., 1915-1991 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Perkins - Columbia Univ. Libraries - Photocopies - "A" (1914-1943) (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Perkins - Columbia Univ. Libraries - Photocopies - "B-Bl" (1924-1954) (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Perkins - Columbia Univ. Libraries - Photocopies - "Bo-Bu" (1919-1946) (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Perkins - Columbia Univ. Libraries - Photocopies - "C" (1919-1945) (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Perkins - Columbia Univ. Libraries - Photocopies - "D" (1919-1948) (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Perkins - Columbia Univ. Libraries - Photocopies - "E-F" (1919-1947) (Box 5, Folder 12)
- Perkins - Columbia Univ. Libraries - Photocopies - "G" (1933-1947) (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Perkins - Columbia Univ. Libraries - Photocopies - "H" (1932-1947) (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Perkins - Columbia Univ. Libraries - Photocopies - "I-J" (1933-1945) (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Perkins - Columbia Univ. Libraries - Photocopies - "K" (1924-1944) (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Perkins - Columbia Univ. Libraries - Photocopies - "L" (1933-1945) (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Perkins - Columbia Univ. Libraries - Photocopies - "M" (1934-1949) (Box 5, Folder 18)
- Perkins - Columbia Univ. Libraries - Photocopies - "O-P" (1934-1945) (Box 5, Folder 19)
- Perkins - Columbia Univ. Libraries - Photocopies - "R" (1929-1948) (Box 5, Folder 20)
- Perkins - Columbia Univ. Libraries - Photocopies - "S" (1933-1945) (Box 5, Folder 21)
- Perkins - Columbia Univ. Libraries - Photocopies - "T" (1938-1947) (Box 5, Folder 22)
- Perkins - Columbia Univ. Libraries - Photocopies - "V-W" (1928-1944) (Box 5, Folder 23)
- Oral History Notes (Box 5, Folder 24)
- Labor Relations: Conciliation (Box 5, Folder 25)
- Social Security - Dept. of Labor, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 26)
- FP Papers - Columbia U. A's, 1931-1944 (Box 5, Folder 27)